RESUME

Chanda Grover

Ph.D. Scholar, Computer Science, Ashoka University, Sonepat. Haryana-131029

Contact No.: (+91) 8744042534 / 9034867690 GITHUB: https://GITHUB.COM/CHANDAGROVER6 E-Mail ID: https://GITHUB.COM/CHANDAGROVER6

Objective

Energetic and passionate student pursuing Ph.D. at the Ashoka University, India. Aiming to utilize my knowledge and skills in the expansion of horizons of research in statistical modelling, machine learning algorithms and its applications .

Skills

Programming Languages : Python, SAS, C.

Scripting Language : Shell Scripting.

Area of interest : Data Analysis, Machine Learning Algorithms,

Statistical Modelling, Probability, Linear Algebra.

Deep Learning Framework : Keras, Tensorflow.

Education Qualification

| Examination | Discipline/ Specialization | School/ College | Year of passing | %age |
|-------------|------------------------------------|--|------------------------------|-------|
| Ph.D. | Computer Science | Ashoka University | January 2019- Pursuing | NA |
| M.Tech | Computer Science | Banasthali Vidyapith | 2014 | 84.83 |
| B. Tech | Computer Science | The Technological Institute Of Textile & Sciences, Bhiwani | 2012 | 78.6 |
| XII | Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics | Vaish Model Sr. Sec. School, Bhiwani | 2008 | 87.6 |
| X | Mathematics, Science, English | Vaish Model Sr. Sec. School, Bhiwani | 2006 | 93.8 |

Work Experience [2014-2018]

1) Research Fellow [July 2017-Dec 2018] at Indian Institute of Technology, Gandhinagar.

1.1) Courses Undertaken:

Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Advanced Algorithms, Computer Systems, Linear Algebra, Probability and Statistics.

1.3) <u>Teaching Assistantship</u>:

Python, Introduction to Machine Learning, Operating System.

1.2) <u>Projects:</u>

- Implemented Fake News Detection using standard classifiers on linguistic based news content features for social media text and reported state-of-art detection results using Keras framework in Python.
- Developed Indian Researcher's Knowledge Base using third party database and extracted the details of Indian authors and papers using machine learning and natural language processing techniques in Python.
- Made the soft robot to locomote from one point to other in smallest distance using evolutionary algorithm in Python.

2) Data Analyst [Sep 2014-July 2017] at Tata Consultancy Services, Delhi.

2.1) *Projects*:

- 2016-2017: Worked as a SAS Developer in a team of three to generate reports for Lloyds Bank Group. Interpreted data from heterogeneous sources using advanced and Base SAS skills. Provided ongoing reports for SAS Aureus Application in an *automatic and efficient way* which helped decision makers to operate the dashboard independently without the intervention of developers.
- 2015-2016: Worked as a SAS developer in a team of four to determine overall health of mobile applications for OTT cockpit project. Designed and Developed Data warehouse by fetching data from various web services like Crittercism, BSM, HPSM and Google Analytics using SAS skills. Offered a real time performance monitoring by introducing *crash reporting service* which helped business users to view errors and issues related to apps and hence to take actions accordingly.
- 2014-2015: Attended Initial Learning Program conducted by Tata Consultancy Services in Business Intelligence and Performance Management. Learnt various skills like SQL, PL/SQL, UNIX, Informatica and Business Objects, Base and Advance SAS and various SAS tools. Certified International level Examination "BASE SAS 9".

Achievements

- Qualified National Level Examination UGC-NET, GATE, JEST in 2016.
- Certified International Level Examination "Base SAS 9" in Sept 2016.
- Second Rank Holder at Masters level in University.
- Awarded Merit Scholarship every year during under graduation.

Date: Jan 8, 2020.